<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>guide on Ubuntu Tutorials</title>
    <link>https://nekocode.github.io/codelabs-hugo-theme/tags/guide/</link>
    <description>Recent content in guide on Ubuntu Tutorials</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nekocode.github.io/codelabs-hugo-theme/tags/guide/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Learn how to create AppArmor profiles to confine your applications.</title>
      <link>https://nekocode.github.io/codelabs-hugo-theme/posts/beginning-apparmor-profile-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nekocode.github.io/codelabs-hugo-theme/posts/beginning-apparmor-profile-development/</guid>
      <description>AppArmor is a Mandatory Access Control (MAC) system which confines programs to a limited set of resources. AppArmor confinement is provided via profiles loaded into the kernel. AppArmor can be set to either enforce the profile or complain when profile rules are violated.
For this tutorial, we will generate an AppArmor profile for certspotter. certspotter is a new utility in Ubuntu as of 17.10 and no profile yet exists. certspotter monitors certificate transparency logs to see if new certificates have been generated for domains listed in a watchlist.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learn how to install, configure and run the fantastic InspIRCd IRC server.</title>
      <link>https://nekocode.github.io/codelabs-hugo-theme/posts/install-irc-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nekocode.github.io/codelabs-hugo-theme/posts/install-irc-server/</guid>
      <description>Despite modern alternatives like Slack, the ancient [IRC][irc-info] is still hugely popular as an online interactive chat platform.
This may be because there are IRC clients for almost every operating system and device, from the Commodore Amiga to your smartphone, and the technology behind IRC is reassuringly simplistic - it really is just raw text and a few control characters being bumped around the network.
Online servers, such as those offered by [Freenode][freenode], are wonderful for both public and private channels.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
